Oh hi! I'm **Annelise Smith**.

I'm a **UX researcher and published psychology professional** with a background in behavioral health and prevention science. I apply qualitative and quantitative user-centered methodologies and build genuine connections with users, asking the right questions to turn data into evidence-based design recommendations.

annelisesmithux@gmail.com bestuxdesignerever.com

Research Experience

UX Research Assistant at Oculus VR

Redmond, WA | Aug 2017 - present

- -Work closely with research scientists to set-up and execute on complex user studies from beginning to end.
- -Coordinate and direct resources and equipment between multiple user studies
- -Collect, store, and analyze study data and present results to lead scientists.
- -Conduct literature reviews and write/submit regulatory documents.

UX Researcher at Republic Development and Design

Seattle, WA | May 2017 - present

- -Work with developers to create UX research test plans, project timelines, test scripts, and screeners, and prototypes for e-commerce websites.
- -Analyze results of user testing and create reports for both the in-house developer team and the client.

UX Researcher at Dive Around the Clock

Seattle, WA | Oct 2016 - May 2017

- -Improved alignment of website with user needs by implementing primary user research plan, including interviews and usability testing.
- -Analyzed data to create personas and user scenarios/journeys.
- -Compiled design recommendations that increased user click-through to donation and volunteer registration pages and enhanced users' feelings of trust.

Research Associate at Washington State University

Pullman, WA | Aug 2011- Aug 2013

- -Managed day-to-day functioning of an NIH-funded research program.
- -Oversaw collection, coding, and analysis of qualitative/quantitative study data.
- -Authored scholarly publications and presented findings to stakeholder groups.
- -Worked with program managers to create and execute on data collection and analysis plans to inform student health services programming.
- -Developed user research plans for student health promotion programs.
- -Designed, implemented, and evaluated studen health promotion campaigns.
- -Wrote briefs/literature reviews to support planning and decision-making.

Other Work Experience

UX Instructor at General Assembly

Seattle, WA | Jan 2017 - present

- -Taught UX research, usability testing, data analysis, interaction design, prototyping, and mobile design classes and workshops.
- -Provided detailed feedback on user research strategy and design projects.

Field Marketing Specialist at Freelance

Seattle, WA | Oct 2015 - Oct 2016

-Devised, organized, and oversaw execution of guerrilla marketing campaigns to drive product awareness and foster brand loyalty.

Top Skills

User Research Usability Testing Ethnography Survey Design Personas Affinity Mapping Journey Mapping Heuristic Evaluation Content Analysis Wireframing Prototyping Data Visualization

Tools I Use

Axure POP Sketch SPSS InVision Stata

OmniGraffle MS Office Suite

HTML/CSS Keynote

Balsamiq Adobe Illustrator

Education

UX Design Immersive (2016) General Assembly Seattle

MA Human Development (2013)

Prevention Science Focus Washington State University

BA Social Sciences (2011)

Minor in Comparative Ethnic Studies Minor in German Washington State University

Published in...

- -Journal of Primary Prevention
- -Journal of Extension
- -Human-Animal Interaction Bulletin

Awards

First Place- CalPal Alexa Skill General Assembly Hackathon (2016)

First Place -AFW Founders Award for Outstanding Graduate Student Washington State University (2013)

First Place- Poster Presentation Wiley Research Exposition Washington State University (2012)